Alvin Tsang

(437) 268-3601 | alvinbno@gmail.com | Toronto, ON

Summary

I am a Front-End Developer with over 3 years of experience creating and designing amazing websites for various clients and businesses using HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React, Angular, Node.js, Bootstrap, Material UI, MongoDB, MySQL, ASP.NET MVC, C#, RESTful APIs, and other web technologies. I want to create beautiful, user-friendly, high-performance websites that bring value and satisfaction to end users.

LinkedIn | Portfolio | Github

Experience

AAS Education Consultancy | Hong Kong Web Developer (Freelance) | 09/2019 - Present

- Modernized design and mobile responsive web layout with Bootstrap 5, HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Optimized webpage loading speed by 25% using AWS CloudFront
- Generated informative charts and graphs for the team leader using Power BI and Google Data Studio with ZohoCRM data
- · Proficient in using Git rebase for history cleanup and branch updates, leading to a more coherent commit history

Rich Fame International Limited | Hong Kong Web developer | 08/2022 - 02/2023

- Built a single web page of a cargo online application system for internal use to replace hand-written legacy to store shipment details using React, Redux, Ant Design, CSS
- Maintain Wordpress website using PHP 7.2, Wordpress 6.1.1, WP Engine by ensuring uptime, fixing bugs and modifying custom theme
- Involved and built a webpage for a Product management system (PMS) using Vue and PHP 5.6
- Integrate RESTful APIs for data retrieval and manipulation within Vue and React applications

Flexsystem | Hong Kong Full Stack Programmer | 05/2021 - 08/2022

- Revamped an existing Angular 1.5 web application to Angular 11 in production for esteemed clients, including the Agricultural Bank of China, HKEAA, Great Eagle, and R&D initiatives
- · Maintained Angular web applications using Angular, Bootstrap 4, C#, and ISAM
- Responsible for building the web layout of a Customer Relationship Management (CRM) using ASP.NET MVC 5, HTML, CSS, jQuery and Entity Framework
- Modernized design and reduced bugs on many Angular widgets
- Implementing CSS3 Grid and Flexbox layouts to create complex and responsive page designs

Skills

Angular, React.js, Tailwind, Material UI, Typescript, CSS, jQuery, ASP.NET MVC, Node.js, RESTful APIs, MongoDB, MySQL, EC2, S3, CloudFront, Git

Education

City University of Hong Kong | Hong Kong Bachelor of Computer Science | 05/2020